Carey Orr Cartoons
Carey Orr Cartoons
- Cartoons
  - 1916-1928
    - The prison door seems to open easier than it closes., 1925; 1925.0127.Orr; no date on cartoon - copyright overlay torn.; Cartoon in two panels: 1. Men are shown shoving a large door to a "prison" shut with a man in the doorway resisting. The signs among the men read: Prosecuting attorney,"The Judge,"12 out of 23 Grand jurors," and "12 Jurors." The scene is labeled "It takes twenty-six men to push it shut - " 2. The door to the "Prison is now open and a "Crook" walks through holding his "Parole" papers. Standing in the shadow of the door "Pulling" it open is a man labeled "His friends." The caption for the scene continues...." - but it doesn't seem to take much 'Pull' to open it!"doodle for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay torn: Reg. U.S. Pa Off; ....by The Chicago ....." (Oversize 9)
    - Perspiring and shivering., 1925; 1925.0128.Orr; A man in the background is cutting logs. The logs are labeled "Orders,"Prosperity,"Industrial outlook," and "Building Boom." The sun is shining and the man is perspiring. The man says "Whew" as he steadily works. In the foreground is a man who is standing in the snow and shivering. His hat is labeled "Stock Market and he says "Br -r-r!" as he looks at a thermometer labeled "Industrial outlook - Drop in Stocks."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 9)
    - Red all over - advertising our state., 1925; 1925.0129.Orr; A man, labeled "Herrin," has a holster with pistols and paints on a " Front Page" of the "World Newspapers" bulletin board " Herrin, Illinois," with a paintbrush dipped in blood from a paint bucket labeled " Murder Savagery.", Illinois is in Williamson County in Southern Illinois. Also known as "Bloody Williamson," after a bloody massacre, brutal battles with the Klan, and a Prohibition war between battling bootleggers." (Oversize 9)
    - The Recognition. Wonder what they see in each other?, 1925; 1925.0130.Orr; A bear and a man come upon one another by a log. On the left is the bear labeled "Soviet Russia" who looks at the man and envisions a plate of bones labeled "Imperial Gov't of Japan." The man in military uniform is labeled "Imperial Japan" and the sheath to his sword is labeled "Siberian penetration." As he sees the bear he envisions himself in a large bear fur coat labeled "Siberian rights."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Remember what happened to the last fellow who tried to ride him., 1925; 1925.0131.Orr; A large horse, labeled "U.S. Citizenry," is wearing a blindfold that is labeled "Volstead act." The horse is tied to a cactus labeled "Dry Amendment." A pilgrim labeled "Dry Ring" is walking to the house with a saddle labeled "Abuse of Political power." In the left background is a grave with a stone labeled "Old Saloon Ring."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay torn: ..Pat Off.; Copyright, 1925, The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Riding on top of the world., 1925; 1925.0132.Orr; The "world" is portrayed as a horse with the globe as the girth of the horse. The horse is angry and snorting with dust kicked up from the hooves of the horse. On top of the horse is "Uncle Sam" with a saddle surrounded by money bags and battleships labeled "Weakened Navy" going around the girth of the horse going around the globe. Uncle Sam looks down at the ships and says, "I'd better fix that girth before I get bucked off!"doodles for cartoon on verso. "Drop in Philippines"Build up the navy."Keep immigration restriction."Economy"How we see to world and how to world see us.'"New Year ins....." Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - The Rabbit Daug., 1925; 1825.0133.Orr; A man labeled "Citizenry" is out hunting with his dog labeled"The Law." A gun labeled "Justice" is over the hunter's shoulder. The dog is heading for a hollowed out log that is labeled "Prohibition offenders," while the hunter frantically pulls the dog's leash. Beneath their feet are the paw prints of a bear labeled "Moron,"Killer,"Thug,"Hold-up"Burglar," and "Murderer."on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.: Copyright: 1925: By The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - The slaughter of the pedestrians., 1925; 1925.0134.Orr; The Roman Colosseum is portrayed with death cloak, skull and sickle as the ceasar. People are in the arena and are labeled "Auto victims." Being released are automobiles with men labeled "Speed maniacs, Careless Drivers," behind them as the gladiators. The spectators are labeled: The rest of us who sit idly by and watch the spectacle."sketch for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 9)
    - Scaring France and hurting Germany., 1925; 1925.0135.Orr; A large jack-in-the-box labeled "German Ballot Box" has been opened by a man labeled "Germany." The man is hit in the head as the lid of the box opens. The face of the toy jack is labeled "Hindenburg Election." The sounds coming from the box are "Internal bitterness over election," and "Civil War Dangers." A young woman labeled "France" is frightened by the face of the jack-in-the-box. "sketches for unknown drawing on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - The spell., 1925; 1925.0136.Orr; The scene similar to Peaceable Kingdom where animals that are hunter/prey relationship in nature are living harmoniously is labeled the "Endorsement of Coolidge." In the background, sitting on the a rock is a Ceasar figure labeled "Coolidge" playing a harp. The music played is "Coolidge Candidacy." Around him are animals sitting in groups: a lion and a lamb, "Conservative" and "Radical"; a fox and a goose, "Anti-leaguer" and "Pro-leaguer;" a dog and cat, "Bonus proponent," and "Bonus Antagonist;" a Cat and mice, "Mutual enemies but pro Coolidge;" and a hawk and bird, "Pro and Con."sketches for unknown drawings on verso. J.C. Dollman painting may be a version of the Hicks' "Peaceable Kingdom." (Oversize 9)
    - Sometimes a bottle makes the best weapon., 1925; 1925.0137.Orr; To the left is a man labeled "Citizenry" who holds in his hand a bottle of "Lawful Beer." He is rolling up his sleeve as he holds the neck of the bottle and looks towards a man labeled "Bootleg ring," who stands in front of barrels of "Poison Whisky" and piles of money labeled "Profits enough to corrupt justice." A man in back of him is labeled "Crime - his partner." On the foreground next to "Citizenry" is a broken club labeled "The Law's Failure."on verso. Torn paper overlay: ..at Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Sorry in the American Home., 1925; 1925.0138.Orr; no date appears on the cartoon as the paper overlay is torn.; A man sits in a chair looking downward as a newspaper lies across his lap. The headlines on the paper read "Bryan Dead." On the wall of the room is a picture labeled "The Great Commoner" with a picture of Bryan. A woman and a boy standing behind the chair gaze at the picture. In the next room of the house is a man, woman and two children, with the man and woman looking into the room."Jennings Bryan (1860-1925): Congressman and three time presidential nominee; a political evangelist, spokesman for liberal causes, closely identified with traditionalism, particularly with Fundamental Christianity. In 1924 he drafted legislation to prevent the teaching of Darwinist evolution in Florida's public schools, and in 1925 served as the prosecution lawyer in the Scopes Trial. Byran won the case, but died less than a week later on July 26, 1925. Preliminary sketches of the profiles of unknown men on the verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 192..., by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - The slur., 1925; 1925.0139.Orr; A man labeled "Pacifist" is dipping his hand s into mud labeled, "Bolshevism, Facifist Doctrine," and is forming mud balls. In the background is the gravestone that reads "Our honored dead." The splattered mud thrown the the stone reads: It is wrong to fight for your country." The stones in the graveyard have on them the years: 1775,"1812,"1848,"186..,"1898," and "1917."sketches for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 9)
    - Swapping problems., 1925; 1925.0140.Orr; no date on cartoon but placed with 1925 cartoons; Two men stand at a fence and hand each other slates. The "South" hands a slate labeled "Race Problems" to the "North." The North hands a slate that says "Labor problem." Each man looks at the other man's slate. At the gate of the fence can be seen the foot prints of people that have left the south labeled "southern labor" going towards the factories of the north."sketches for unknown drawing on verso as well as for cartoon. "Keep labor out."South"Negro laborers from South"Mexico recognition." (Oversize 9)
    - Starting his hatch early., 1925; 1925.0141.Orr; Al Smith" is standing in a barnyard holding a large crate labeled "1928 Dem. Presidential Nomination." Laying on the straw on top is a large egg labeled "Smith Candidacy." A hen is in the foreground and labeled "Dem. Party." Al Smith says, "Chickie, Chickie." In the background peeking over the fence are men labeled "Rival Democrats."on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.: copyright: 1925: By The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Searching our homes. A part of the prohibition program., 1925; 1925.0142.Orr; Police officers are going through a home trying to find alcohol. A neighbor is at his fence and a police officer says, "You're under arrest for interfering with an officer of the law!" The neighbor replies, "But I only asked what the trouble was." A police officer in the basement of the home has taken a drink from a bottle and says, "K-Kah! Vinegar!" Officers are checking for alcohol in a fire extinguisher, perfume bottle, and a milk bottle. An officer calls out the window, "Say Chief, C'mon in! The old lady is beginning to break down." Inside the house an officer is saying to a woman, "Cut out the whimpering, an' answer my question! Where have you got the stuff hidden?" A man calls out the door, "Chief, did you bring a jimmy? I want to pry open a drawer." The chief, with the look of anger on his face, has just kicked the family dog."on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Stealing their stuff., 1925; 1925.0143.Orr; A man is going through a garbage can pulling out objects. The man is wearing a crown that is labeled "Dictatorial Powers" and he is labeled "Our Bigots - Self appointed rulers of America. Under his arm is a tablet that reads "Can do no wrong" and he carries a robe. He is reaching in a trash can, that is filled with an "Emperor" and "King," for a staff that is labeled "Divine Right to Rule."preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Still fighting., 1925; 1925.0144.Orr; A man labeled "Anti-Saloon league" is in a street taking punches and swings at the air. In the distance can be seen an officer, labeled "U.S. Gov't" taking away a man labeled, "The Old Saloon." Looking down from a window is a man labeled "Public" that is scratching his head."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Finding Willie is getting to be quite a task., 1925; 1925.0145.Orr; no date appears on cartoon, but placed with 1925 cartoons; Cartoon in three panels: 1. A mother labeled "McAdoo Democrats," exclaims, "Mercy Me!" as she sees her son labeled "Wm G. McAdoo." He walks in the house covered with oil and is labeled "Oil Scandal." 2. The mother can seen hanging her son's clothes out on the clothes line and she calls out to him, "Now, William, do be careful!" McAdoo has been giving a "Clean Bill of Health" as he walks to his "Political back yard." 3. The mother who is washing exclaims "William?" as she sees her son covered in oil again and is labeled "More Oil."sketches for unknown drawing on verso. (Oversize 9)
    - She's going to make enemies for us., 1925; 1925.0146.Orr; Uncle Sam is sitting in a chair as a beautiful woman labeled "Prosperity" hands him a rose. He says to the woman as he looks out the window, "The sweeter you smile upon me, the sourere they look!" Outside, men can be seen through the window. They are labeled, "Foreign Jealousy,"Envy," and "Growing ill will toward U.S."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off. Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Seven years ago today., 1925; 1925.0147.Orr; Uncle Sam stands looking at a picture and says, "If the world would always remember how thankful it once was for peace - there would never be another war." The picture is of a soldier on a bended knee with hands clasped. The soldier labeled "The World" has a face that is bandaged and is a caricature of a globe. He stands with a cemetary to his left and destroyed buildings to the right. The picture is labeled "Armistice Day - Nov 11, 1918."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Still unrecognized, but they're beginning to notice him.", 1925; 1925.0148.Orr; Two men are walking on a snow covered street. They are labeled "Italy" and "France" and their footprints make the shape of a dollar sign. Uncle Sam is walking out of their way. His girth is enormous and is labeled "Unrecognized debt to U.S." He says "How d' do!" to the two men and they mumble back to him."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Still piling them on., 1925; 1925.0149.Orr; A woman labeled "Law makers" is piling packages and bundles labeled "Laws" onto a man labeled "American Citizen. The contents of the packages are piled so high onto him that many are breaking and spilling on to the ground. A janitor is there mopping up the mess. The janitor is labeled "Law enforcer" and his broom is labeled "Police duties." The puddle from all the broken "Laws" is labeled "Law Breaking."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary doodle for cartoon on verso. "Individual Freedom." (Oversize 9)
    - Spoiling their trysting place., 1925; 1925.0150.Orr; Uncle Sam is sitting on a park bench with a beautiful young woman. They each are sitting at opposite ends. In back of the bench is a tree with a branch that extends over them with a large hornet's nest hanging between them. The nest is labeled "Unsettled debt question," and bees are flying all around. On the tree is carved a heart with "F. U.S." in it. The dates 1777 and 1917 are carved into the tree."overlay: Re. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - Spirited animals are easier led than driven., 1925; 1925.0151.Orr; Cartoon in three panels: 1. A horse in the shape of the United States is peacefully being lead by a man labeled "Moral & Economic suasion," and "Temperance movement." Behind the horse, a man is chopping down a sapling. The man is dressed in black and labeled "Dry." 2. "Dry" now takes a switch labeled "Dry law" and hits the back of "U.S.A." 3. "U.S.A" bucks and kicks "Dry" and knocks over "Temperance movement."doodles for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 9)
    - The strenuous life of our mechanical age., 1925; 1925.0152.Orr; A man labeled "Pa" is standing talking to a man labeled "Our inventors" that is working at a draftsman table. Plans and "ideas" are scattered on the floor and around the room. Pa says, "Listen, Mr. Inventor, I'm just a plain family man, who loves to make his family happy. When you got up the talking machine, they wanted one, so I bought it. A few years later I scrapped up enough money to buy one of your flivvers then you thought up a lot of other things they had to have - I've been buying'em as fast as I could and I'm still an electric ice box, an oil heater, an electric sewing machine and a six tube radio set behind! - an' if you don't lay off and take a vacation, you're goin'' to make a bum outa me!"overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Flivver: a small cheap usually old automobile. Preliminary sketches for unknown cartoon on verso." (Oversize 9)
    - Strengthening the wall., 1925; 1925.0153.Orr; A man labeled "Europe" is doing masonry repair on a wall labeled "Germany, "England,"France,"Belgium,"Italy," and "Poland." In one hand is a trowel he is using to apply the "Locarno Security Pact." Behind the wall peeking over is a bear that is labeled "Russian Menace."1925, Germany, France and England made a series of treaties in Locarno, Switzerland. This new spirit of co- operation between the countries pledging never to go to war against each other and to respect the demilitrized zone in the Rhineland. They pledged to guarantee the borders of the three states. Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Re. U.S. Pat. Off.: Copyright: 1925: By The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - They had better begin unloading that camel pretty soon., 1925; 1925.0154.Orr; A camel labeled "France" has an enormous load of straw that is piled on its back. The straw is labeled "Debts - Financial troubles - Military Burdens - Preparedness against Germany." A man on a ladder is standing at the top and placing a rifle to the top of the load. The rifle is labeled "Riff war - The Last Straw?"overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - untitled, 1925; 1925.0155.Orr; Cartoon in eleven panels; the first nine are portraits of individuals: 1. "This is the murderer." 2. "This is the high priced lawyer retained to hang the jury instead of the crook." 3. "This is his friend with a political pull who does all he can to obstruct the law." 4. "This is the judge who is convinced that criminals are children and not responsible." 5. "This is the soft hearted juror who believes it a sin to hang any one. " 6. "This is the sob sister who appeals to the governor to pity and pardon his fellow man." 7. "This is the governor who grants reprives and stays, and stays and reprieves, etc." 8. "This is a member of the pardon board who pardons and pardons & pardons." 9. "This is one of the many crooks who are willing to kill at any time." 10. "Here are the hundreds of future victims of murderers who believe that the law is a joke." 11. "These are the men who are as much to blame in the eyes of justice as if they had fired the shots themselves." Here the people are labeled: Sob lawyer,"sob friend,"sob judge,"sob juror,"sob sister,"sob governor," and "sob pardon board."sketches to unknown drawing on verso. Torn paper overlay: Reg U.S. Pat Off.; copy...by The Chicago Trib....." Sob sister: a sentimental and often impractical person usually engaged in good works." (Oversize 9)
    - A temporary relief, but a permanent injury.", 1925; 1925.0156.Orr; A man in tattered and torn clothing is labeled "European debtor nation." He is surrounded by pieces of paper labeled "Unrecognized debt," and "Unpaid debt." He is giving himself an injection with a hypodermic needle that is labeled "New Loan." The man seems to look invigorated and says, "A-a-a-a-h!!"overlay: Reg. U.S. Patent Office. ©.) 1925: The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - There must be some reason., 1925; 1925.0157.Orr; A man labeled "organized crime" is holding a rope labeled "Political pull." Attached to the other end of the rope is a bull dog labeled "The Law." The dog is trying to attack the man but can not reach him as they are going around a large barrel labeled "$2,650,000,000.)) - Hold-ups - Robberies - Confidence Game in 1924." The barrel is filled with money. In the background is a man labeled "Citizen" that is scratching his head and asking "Wonder why he can't catch him?"overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - There seems to be some difference of opinion., 1925; 1925.0158.Orr; Dressed a cowboys from the west shooting it out are two men labeled "Hearst" and "Al Smith" The card table that was knocked over is labeled "N.Y. City - Political Game." On the wall is a pictured labeled "Our Mayor" with bullet holes through it. Standing in the background is a man labeled "Knickerbocker."overlay: Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary doodle on background." (Oversize 9)
    - Trying to tackle the whole team., 1925; 1925.0159.Orr; On a football field a player labeled "Police dep't" and "Law enforcement" is blocking a group of players labeled "Volstead violator,"Violator of boxing law," and "Violators of Petty laws" Going down the field with the ball in the opposite direction is a man labeled "Criminal" and carrying a football labeled "Crime." In the background "Father Dearborn" says to "Coach Dever,"Why don't you concentrate on the man with the ball?" In the stands the spectators are yelling "STOP CRIME."sketch for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - The three-legged stool., 1925; 1925.0160.Orr; A stool labeled "Our Security" has three extremely long legs. They are labeled "Air Defense,"Naval Defenses" and "Land Defense." An "Air Partisan" is pointing to a leg saying "This leg is the most important - The other two depend upon it!" A "Navy" officer says "It's the least important - it has to depend upon these two!" Sitting at the top of the stool trying to eat a dinner labeled "Peace" and "Tranquility" is a man labeled "The rest of us." Lying on the foreground is a hand saw labeled "Defense alterations."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 9)
    - The twisted American., 1925; 1925.0161.Orr; The caption for the cartoon reads: The Citizen who isn't the least bit frightened at the muzzle of a gun - but is scared to death at the breech." The upper scene shows a man labeled "Pacifist" who stands in front of a fun labeled "Foreign preparations for war." The bottom scene shows the same man yelling, "Oh-oooo Help! Murder! Save Me!" with a large gun labeled "U.S. War defenses."sketches for unknown drawing on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1925, by The chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)
    - That act isn't going over so good., 1925; 1925.0162.Orr; A man labeled "Higher ups" is controlling the marionettes in a small theater labeled "The Druggan Scandal." One marionette is sitting in a chair with a large bundle of money next to him and labeled "Millionair bootlegger." Next to him, an officer is prostrating himself and is labeled "The Law." The string attached to the marionettes is labeled "Political Pull." Sitting watching the performance and getting angry is a man labeled "public."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." Preliminary sketches for unknown drawing on verso. Terry Druggan was a prohibition era bootlegger in charge of the Valley Gang - West Side Liquor distributors who were bigger than Al Capone in the early years of the 1920's before the Chicago Rackets were consolidated. Terry Druggan revealed to members of a federal grand jury how accommodating the Sheriff and Warden could be while in jail." (Oversize 9)
    - They want us to turn around and go back., 1925; 1925.0163.Orr; Uncle Sam is standing on the shores of the U.S.A. dressed as a pilgrim. He holds a U.S. Flag that says "Independence," and stands next to a turkey labeled "Prosperity and food crops labeled "Every blessing in the world to be thankful for." In a rowboat labeled "Our internationalists" is a pilgrim pointing to a large sailing ship in the distance labeled "World Court."paper overlay: ...t, 1925, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 9)